Guide to the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham, NC records, 1894-1992 RL.11616
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham, NC records
1894-1992
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Young Women's Christian Association (Durham, N.C.)
RL.11616
110 Linear Feet
The Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham was founded in 1920 and served the larger Durham community from the 1920s until the 1970s. The Harriet Tubman branch of the Durham YWCA served the African-American community in particular and, through collaboration with the Central branch, fostered integration in a racically segregated Durham. In the 1970s, the YWCA became the home of the Durham Women's Health Co-op and the Durham Rape Crisis Center, which operated out of the YWCA Women's Center. These organizations were central to reform movements throughout Durham, from women's health and childcare to fair wages and civil rights. The YWCA of Durham records reflect both the administrative history of the YWCA, as well as the programs, projects, social events, and community outreach that formed the backbone of the organization. For example, a series of scrapbooks, put together by Y Teen groups, program participants, and residents of the YWCA's boarding houses captures the strength of the YWCA community. The broader impact of the YWCA is evident in their range of programming, especially the clubs they hosted, from PMS and Single Mothers groups to a "Matrons Club." The YWCA's impact is also reflected in administrative and financial materials that tell the story of the Y's work to serve the people of Durham that needed a safe place to build community for themselves and their families.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: Administrative, Program, and Community Outreach.
Banner
Portions of this collection are closed for processing.
Provenance
The Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham, NC records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 1991-2005.
Related Materials
Gilda Nance papers; Margery Sved papers; Harriet Tubman Branch Annual Report cataloged separately as serial; Ladyslipper Inc. records; Mandy Carter papers
Collection Overview
The Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham was founded in 1920 and served the larger Durham community from the 1920s until the 1970s. The Harriet Tubman branch of the Durham YWCA served the AfricanAmerican community in particular and, through collaboration with the Central branch, fostered integration in a radically segregated Durham. In the 1970s, the YWCA became the home of the Durham Women's Health Co-op and the Durham Rape Crisis Center, which operated out of the YWCA Women's Center. These organizations were central to reform movements throughout Durham, from women's health and childcare to fair wages and civil rights. The YWCA of Durham records reflect both the administrative history of the YWCA, as well as the programs, projects, social events, and community outreach that formed the backbone of the organization. For example, a series of scrapbooks, put together by Y Teen groups, program participants, and residents of the YWCA's boarding houses captures the strength of the YWCA community. The broader impact of the YWCA is evident in their range of programming, especially the clubs they hosted, from PMS and Single Mothers groups to a "Matrons Club." The YWCA's impact is also reflected in administrative and financial materials that tell the story of the Y's work to serve the people of Durham that needed a safe place to build community for themselves and their families.
Conditions Governing Access
Portions of this collection are closed for processing.
Young Women's Christian Association (Durham, N.C.) -- History; Durham Women's Health Co-op (Durham, N.C.); Durham Rape Crisis Center (Durham, N.C.); African Americans -- Durham (N.C.) -- History; Durham (N.C.) -- History; Women -- Services for -- North Carolina -- Durham; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Administrative Files, 1894-1992
  - Director/Executive Office Files, 1926-1988; 1
    - Executive Office Files, 1926-1983; 5 boxes (Box 1-5)
      General
      arranged chronologically
      Scope and Contents
      Files from the Executive Office of YWCA Durham, including the Harriet Tubman Branch and the files of Dorothea Burton, Carolyn Greene, Geraldine Mitchell, and Rupart Blanchard Includes materials such as reports to national, financial papers, building repairs and building addition reports/finanacal campaigns, basic standards of the YWCA, board meeting minutes and attendance sheets, United Fund correspondence and budgets, World YWCA materials, Operation Breakthrough proposals and funding, various pamphlets for women's programs, self study, association review, program priorities, personnel contracts and committee materials, and National Statistical Reports.
    - Past President's Files, 1984-1988; 1 boxes (Box 6)
      Files of former president's of YWCA of Durham including Czerni Brasuell, Viven Patterson Includes materials such as program reports, board minutes, board elections and resignations, national public affairs/policy newsletters, Women of Achievement nominations and awards, United Way board materials, leadership development files, Durham YWCA newsletters, budgets, mailing list materials, community events and resources, 5K race details and organization, and various program information.
    - Correspondence, 1943-1959; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Personnel Policies, 1954 (Box 6)
    - NC College Advisory Committee, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Workman's Comp and Liability Insurance, 1955-1964 (Box 6)
    - Colonial Life Insurance, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Status of Women in North Carolina Report, 1974 (Box 7)
      Report by the North Carolina Commission on the Education and Employment of Women.
    - Personnel Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - Durham City Directory, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Public Affairs, 1976-1979 (Box 7)
    - Public Relations Materials, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Building and Membership Sampling, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - Staff Meetings, 1981-1983 (Box 7)
    - Voluntary Action Leadership newsletter, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Membership, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Annual Reports and Membership, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
    - Personnel Policies, 1984; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Public Affairs, 1984 (Box 7)
    - National Board Correspondence, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Executive Director Search, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - PR, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Health Care Plan, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Welcome Reception for Czerni Brasuell as Executive Director of Durham YWCA, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Membership Info, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Memos/Accounting, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1985-10 (Box 7)
    - Executive Director Reports, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Performance Appraisal, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Garden Club Luncheon, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Memos, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
      Memos from Czerni Brasuell to staff and board.
    - Soccer, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Socially Responsible Investing, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Staff Reports, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Board Nominees, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Needs Assessment-Durham County, 1985 (Box 7)
    - CZ (Czerni Brasuell) Papers, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Nominating Committee, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Insurance, 1986 (Box 8)
      Insurance policies--fire, building, commercial.
    - Workman's Compensation Approval, 1986 (Box 8)
    - YWCA Materials for Sale, 1986 (Box 8)
    - YWCA Memos, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Czerni Brasuell Personnel File, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
      Materials related to her appointment as executive director.
    - United Way, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Czerni Brasuell correspondence, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Board of Directors, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Women of Achievement, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Memos to Staff, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Personnel Files, 1963-1987 (Box 8)
      Former Staff files, name files (including Roderick Hayes, Marilyn Fichman, Maryann Fischler, Marian Ciriano, Wendy Bearman, Deborah Long, Constance Renz, Mary Belle Hudson, Deborah Wilson, and Lauri Silverman), personnel leave records, summary of benefits, timesheets, payroll statements, application flow charts, and Labor Fair Standards Act, Day Camp Workers (1979)
    - Personnel - Miss Buirl, 1963-1964 (Box 33)
    - Personnel - Juanita Wilson, 1964-1965 (Box 33)
    - YWCA Organizational chart (Box 33)
    - ERA Coalition NC, 1970-1978 (Box 33)
    - YWCA Women's Movement and Equal Rights Legislation, 1975-1976 (Box 33)
    - Staff Memos, 1976-1979 (Box 33)
    - Staff Appraisals, 1976-1978 (Box 33)
    - Constance Renz, 1978-1982 (Box 33)
    - Maryann Fischler, 1979-1982 (Box 33)
    - Personnel, 1979-1980 (Box 33)
    - Former Staff, 1980-1982 (Box 33)
    - Durham YWCA Personnel Policy, 1983 (Box 33)
    - Board Training, 1983 (Box 33)
    - Board Current Items, 1984 (Box 33)
    - National YWCA Correspondence, 1984 (Box 33)
    - Board Calendar, 1984 (Box 33)
    - Marilyn Fichman, 1984 (Box 33)
    - RE: Correspondence Staff, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Budgets RCC, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Director's Reports, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Projected RCC Budgets, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Mail Permit, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Computer, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Social Action, 1985 (Box 33)
    - RCC Advisory Minutes Committee Protocol, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Transmittals, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Safety Inspections, 1986 (Box 33)
    - RCC Companions, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Thank Yous, 1986 (Box 33)
    - Thank Yous - Donations, 1986 (Box 33)
    - PR (Czerni Brasuell), 1986 (Box 33)
    - Agency Objectives, 1987 (Box 33)
    - Women of Achievement, 1988 (Box 33)
    - Memos to Staff, 1988 (Box 33)
    - Board of Directors, 1988 (Box 33)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Supplemental Materials, 1989 (Box 40)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Supplemental Material, 1990 (Box 40)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Supplemental Material, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Supplemental Material, 1991-1992 (Box 40)
    - Center for Women's Advancement, 1988-1989 (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 40)
  - National YWCA Files, 1939-1989; 4
    - National YWCA Convention Materials, 1982 (Box 33)
    - National Convention Book, 1958 (Box 33)
    - National Convention Book, 1964 (Box 33)
    - National Convention Book, 1970 (Box 33)
    - Conferences, 1934-1941 (Box 31)
    - National YWCA Materials, 1939-1943 (Box 31)
    - Executive Directors Conference, 1945 (Box 31)
    - YWCA National Convention, 1946 (Box 31)
    - Girl Reserve Summer Camp, 1946 (Box 31)
    - National Industrial Assembly, 1947 (Box 31)
    - Negro Leadership Conference, 1948 (Box 31)
    - National Convention Book, 1958 (Box 33)
    - National Convention Book, 1964 (Box 33)
    - National Materials, 1965-1982 (Box 31)
      Reports, programs, national convention/conference materials.
    - National Convention Book, 1970 (Box 31)
    - YWCA National Workplan Guidelines, 1973-1975 (Box 31)
    - National Administrative Volunteers Management Training Manual, 1975 (Box 31)
    - Racial Justice Action Handbook, 1975 (Box 31)
      Handbook created by the Racial Justice Task Force of the Baltimore YWCA and adapted to be utilized nationwide
    - National Convention workbook, 1976 (Box 31)
    - National Board of the YWCA "Looking to the Future: A Plan for Study and Action", 1977 (Box 31)
    - Public Affairs newsletters, 1977-1979 (Box 31)
    - YWCA Action Audit for Change, 1978 (Box 31)
    - National Conference Report for YWCA Program Staff, 1979 (Box 31)
    - Presidential Leadership and Association Committee Chairpersons' Workshop, 1979 (Box 31)
    - National Board YWCA Learning Center Public Relations Management Workshop, 1979 (Box 31)
    - National Correspondence, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - National YWCA Convention Materials, 1980-1982; 10 folders (Box 31-32)
      includes pre-convention bulletins, convention issues, preparation meetings, the Durham delegation meetings, correspondence, resolutions, and the convention program
    - National YWCA Leadership Development Center, 1982 (Box 32)
    - National Public Policy Program, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Public Policy materials, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Annual Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 32)
      Includes "The Print Out" annual report of YWCA data, "Get Your Annual Meeting Squared Away" annual meeting handbook, and 1985-86 annual report on diversity in action.
    - New Worker's Packet, 1984 (Box 32)
    - Durham YWCA National Association Review, 1984 (Box 32)
    - National YWCA Board Orientation of New Directors, 1985 (Box 32)
    - National YWCA Convention Amendments, 1985 (Box 32)
    - Management for Executive Staff Workshop, 1985 (Box 32)
    - YWCA Staff Development I New Worker's Packet, 1985 (Box 32)
    - YWCA Staff Development I Supervisor's Packet, 1985 (Box 32)
    - National YWCA Materials, 1985-1986 (Box 32)
    - YWCA National Standards, 1985-1988 (Box 32)
    - South Africa Program, 1986 (Box 32)
    - National Board, 1987 (Box 32)
    - YWCA National Policy on Males, 1988 (Box 32)
    - YWCA National Convention Action, 1988 (Box 32)
    - YWCA National Recruitment Handbook, 1988 (Box 32)
    - Consideration of Durham for National Convention site, 1988 (Box 32)
    - National Association of YWCA Executives conference letter, 1989 (Box 32)
  - Financial, 1929-1992; 2
    - Receipts and Disbursement Book, 1929-1932 (Box 9)
    - Receipts, 1939-1945 (Box 9)
    - Audit Reports and Finincial Statements, 1945-1965 (Box 9)
    - Receipts, 1946-1947 (Box 9)
    - Residence Budget, 1949 (Box 9)
    - YWCA Special Building Fund Campaign, 1950-1954 (Box 9)
    - Receipts, 1951-1954 (Box 9)
    - Financial Sheets, 1955-1958 (Box 9)
    - Endowment Funds, 1960-1978 (Box 9)
    - Audit Reports, 1962-1968 (Box 9)
    - Sales and Use Tax Reports, 1965-1973 (Box 9)
    - Braswell Memorial Fund, 1967 (Box 9)
    - NC Beverage Account Reports, 1968-1975 (Box 9)
    - Audit Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 9)
    - Grant Information, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Budget, 1970-1973 (Box 9)
    - Audit Reports, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
    - Reciept Book, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - Finance Reports and Ledgers, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Fundraising, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Finance Deferred Giving Resources, 1975-1978 (Box 9)
    - Appraisal of YWCA properties in Durham, NC, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Coca-Cola Vouchers and Bank Statements, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Auditor, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Program Scholarship Funds, 1976-1978 (Box 9)
    - Humanities Grant for Battered Women, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Budget Preparation, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Budgets, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Finance Reports, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Federal Regualtions for the Administration of Grants, 1978 (Box 10)
    - YWCA Estate Planning, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Fundraising Materials, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Finance, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Ledger, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Loan Agreement: Furniture, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Cash Receipts Journal and Payroll Summary, 1979 (Oversize-box 2)
    - Reciepts and Invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Report of the Fundraising Potential of the Durham YWCA, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Finance, 1980 (Box 10)
    - General Journal, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
    - Capital Funds, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Financial Report Worksheets, 1980 (Box 10)
    - YWCA Memorial Fund, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Checks and Invoices, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Cash Receipts Journal and Checking Account Deposit Tickets, 1980 (Oversize-box 2)
    - United Way Policies and Procedures, 1981-1983 (Box 11)
    - Energy Saving Program, 1981-1988 (Box 11)
    - Sales Tax and Use Report, 1981 (Box 11)
    - General Ledger and Cash Receipts Journal, 1981 (Oversize-box 2)
    - Finance Committee, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Monthly Income Budgets, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Finance Committee, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Receipts and Invoices, 1983 (Box 11-12)
    - General Ledger, 1983 (Box 12)
    - General Ledger, 1984; 6 folders (Box 12)
    - United Way Budget, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Accounts Paid, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Gulf Energy Invoices, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Employee Earnings and Donations, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Grants, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Finance Policies and Procedures, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Charge Backs, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Morning Child Care Expense Information, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Monthy Reports Budget, 1985-07 (Box 12)
    - IRS Correspondence, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Equipment Inventory List, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Sales Tax Refund, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Program Budgets, 1985 (Box 13)
      Adult Programs, Teens, and Rape Crisis Center budgets.
    - Monthly Expenditures, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Budget Forms, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Audit, 1985; 5 folders (Box 13)
    - Investment Reports, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Ledger and Balance Sheets, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Payroll and Salaries Ledger, 1986 (Box 13)
    - General Ledger, 1986 (Oversize-box 1)
    - Budget, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Women of Achievement Budget, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Investments, C/D's Mutual Fund, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Program Budget and Adult Services, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Salary Breakdown, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Revised Budget, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Bill Requesting $150,000 from State of NC, 1987 (Box 13)
    - The Raising of Money book, 1987 (Box 13)
      Essential guide for trustees
    - Budget Analysis, 1987 (Box 13)
    - CD Worksheets, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Investment, 1987; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Budget, 1987 (Box 13)
    - United Way Presentations, 1988 (Box 13)
    - United Way Agency Meetings and Environmental Scan, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Budget United Way Proposal, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence about United Way Allocations, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    - Non-profit Grant Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
      Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation and Mary Reynold Babcock Foundation
    - Healthcare Benefits and Rates, 1989 (Box 13)
    - United Way Executive Forum and Organization nominations, 1989 (Box 13)
    - United Way Allocations, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Unemployment Tax Report, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Morning Child Care/Program Receipts, 1982-1986 (Box 14-18)
      Includes photocopies of MCC/Program receipts.
    - Morning Child Care, Afterschool, and Day Camp Ledgers and Participant Lists, 1983; 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Checks from YWCA, 1977-1987 (Box 18-20)
      Checks written from the YWCA account for salaries, services, refunds, etc. Includes the ledger for checks written and deposited, as well as bank statements and deposit records. A portion of the checks for 1986 in Oversize Box 1.
    - Payment receipts and invoices, 1980-1987 (Box 21-23)
      1982 and 1984 arranged by month. 1985-1987 arranged alphabetically by vendor, with petty cash reciepts at the beginning.
    - Child Victim Services/Volunteers, 1988 (Box 42)
      Contains newspaper clippings that speak to why the Rape Crisis Center of Durham disaffiliated from the Durham YWCA.
    - Grants (Durham City Proposal), 1986-1989 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham City Reports), 1984-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Correspondence), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Proposal), 1984-1985 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Proposal), 1985-1986 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Proposal), 1986-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Proposal), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Proposal), 1988-1989 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Durham County Reports), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (F.I.P.S.E.), 1988-1989 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Florence Rogers Charitable Trust), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Fund for Southern Communities, 1986 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Fund for Southern Communities), 1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Greater Durham Community), 1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Edward Hazen Foundation), 1987-1989 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Helena Rubinstein Foundation), 1986 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Holly Hill), 1985-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Janirve Foundation), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (JM Foundation), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (The Junior League), 1986 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Kate B. Reynolds Health Care Trust), 1986 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Mary Y. Berman Trust), 1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (MS. Foundation), 1983-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (National Center Pre/Control of Rape), 1981-1982 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Proposal), 1983-1984 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Proposal), 1984-1985 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Proposal), 1985-1986 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Proposal), 1986-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Proposal), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Reports), 1983-1984 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Reports), 1984-1985 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NCCSW Reports), 1986-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NC Fund for Children & Families), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (NC Humanities Committee), 1985-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Resist Martial Arts), 1986-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Smith Richardson Vicks), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Society Non-Profit Agencies), n.d. (Box 42)
    - Grants (Special Legislation), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (United Way), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (United Way Fundraising Policy), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (United Way Position Gay/Lesbian), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (United Way UWASIS Codes), n.d. (Box 42)
    - Grants (Ventana Press), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (VOCA), 1985 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Whitener Foundation), 1987-1988 (Box 42)
    - Grants (WTAP), 1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Z Smith Reynolds Proposal), 1984 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Z Smith Reynolds), 1986-1987 (Box 42)
    - Grants (Z Smith Reynolds), 1987-1989 (Box 42)
    - Fundraising (Balloon Lift), 1988 (Box 42)
    - Fundraising (June Proclamations), 1986-1988 (Box 42)
    - Fundraising (New Productions, Inc.), 1988 (Box 42)
    - Fundraising (Donations, Public), 1988 (Box 42)
    - Budgets for Teen/Low Income Women Programs, 1988 (Box 42)
    - Flyers, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Board of Directors, 1894-1990; 3
    - Maude Cuney Hare letter, September 12, 1894 (Box 23)
      Maud Cuney Hare of Boston writes to the "Secretary of the YWCA" to ask to book a "costume recital" in Durham. She writes, "Our new program is an especially attractive one, in that the first part is given in constume true to the Orient and the Tropics - the music is that of the darker races." Cuney writes that they've "been accepted by a white manager" who has booked them for white Women's Clubs.
    - List of the first members of the Board of Directors, [1920s] (Box 23)
    - Ralph P. Rogers letter, [1920s] (Box 23)
      Ralph P. Rogers of Rogers Drug Company writes on company letterhead to Rev. Samuel L. McDowell to inquire if he has, "any reliable colored girl who would like to help around a home." He goes on to specify that he's looking for a girl of "about 12, 13, 14, or 15 yrs. old."
    - Harriet Tubman Branch materials, [1920s] (Box 23)
    - Harriet Tubman branch bylaws, [1920s] (Box 23)
    - Tubman Branch information, [1922] (Box 23)
    - Correspondence and Board Materials, [1922] (Box 23)
    - Blank book of YWCA room registry forms, [1922] (Box 23)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1920-1922 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, Scholarship, Resolution, [1922] (Box 23)
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1922-1924 (Box 23)
      Contains the constitution of the Harriet Tubman Branch and programming information
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1923-1925 (Box 23)
    - Minutes of the Committee of Management, 1923-1933 (Box 23)
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1924 (Box 23)
      Harriet Tubman Branch
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1924-1926 (Box 23)
    - Deeds on Property, 1924-1957 (Box 24)
      Board of Trustees correspondence, deeds, and insurance papers.
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1926-1929 (Box 24)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1928-1943 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1930-1932 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1930-1933 (Box 24)
    - Board Reports, 1930-1944 (Box 24)
    - Personnel, Business, and Industrial Committees, 1931-1957 (Box 24)